<resources>
    <string name="app_name">MyFinalProject</string>
    <string name="spring">Very little compares with the gentle ebb and flow of the surface as you glide out over a pike lake in the early springtime. Just knowing there are big pike somewhere in the depths gets the heart beating a little faster. This is the time of year for pike; right now is your best shot at tangling with trophy-class northerns.Understanding a bit of pike biology and how these razor-toothed predators relate to habitat during the post-spawn period is the key to success. Many waters are just opening up to anglers and the pike are ripe for the taking.The first thing to know is that while pike are aggressive in the summer, they can be downright finicky while recovering from the rigors of spawning activity.The second thing is that these “water wolves” aren’t always ravenous. Most pike begin feeding heavily when the water temperatures reach the 55- to 60-degree range and go into the spring feeding frenzy when it climbs to 65 degrees.Spring may be the best time of the year to be on the water but some anglers still go home empty handed. If you’re wondering about the best way to tempt a big pike in the spring, here are some tactics that you can take to the bank.Find green vegetation and you’ll find pike. Submerged weeds that have wintered over and remained green are pike magnets. Developing bulrushes in shallow water hold their share of pike as well. Combine these features with deep water and you’re on high-percentage spots.Admittedly, several tactics work in the weeds as the water warms up but in the post-spawn period, finesse is the name of the game. Set the dinner table with offerings of slow-moving soft plastics that big northern pike just can’t resist.Toss oversized plastic minnows, lizards, and grubs on 1/4- or 1/2-ounce jigs to the outside edges of the weeds. Green beds of cabbage and other long-stalked weeds in water 6 to 10 feet deep are ideal. Let the bait glide naturally to the bottom and rest for a moment before shaking it with your rod tip. Repeat the process as you lift and glide the bait along the outside edge. Anything that appears to be dying qualifies as a meal worth chasing as far as early-season pike are concerned. Plastics fished that way seldom get slammed and a little tick on the line may be all you’ll feel.
</string>

    <string name="autumn">Muskie maniacs and steelheaders will disagree, but I think fall pike are bigger, tougher, and meaner than any other fish in Ontario. They also among the most mysterious. I am convinced that really huge pike, the ones said to eat adult loons and pull stringers of walleye off boats, are most catchable in fall, when their preferred forage species move shallow to spawn. The rest of the time, except after spawning in spring, monster pike are feeding deep in the bowels of lakes, out of reach to most anglers.My best fall pike measured 46 inches (117 cm) and weighed about 30 pounds (13.6 kg), but had bigger fish follow baits. These 50-inch (127-cm) creatures, with the girth of a pickle barrel, are frightening. I love muskie, but given the option of tackling a 30-pound muskie or a pike, take the pike any day. The reason is simple; a 30-pound pike is a rarer beast and will fight harder and longer than a muskie. It is also a tougher fish to fool. Giant pike like cold water. This is a good thing for autumn pike anglers, as fall brings a massive cooling trend to the pikes world. Pike over 20 pounds (9 kg) are uncomfortable in water much warmer than 65 F (18 C). In fact, some of my best fall pike have been taken in water below 50 F (10 C).There are natural clues to watch for if you like pike too. Stable high-pressure systems in fall mean it is time to go fishing. Bright days and cool nights are also a good bet after the first hard frost. When these events occur, giant gators get growly sounds in their stomachs. Cooling water sends them out hunting.Much of their fall forage is on obvious structure. Fall pike areas include main-lake points, extensive rock reefs (look for marker buoys), saddles between islands, and remaining green cabbage weeds. If these simple lake elements are associated with deep water, so much the better..After this fish, I decided to change my setup around. I used a lures instead of a wobbled deadbait, and instead of my legered static dead, I cast out my wobbling rig freelined, with only two swan shot pinched on the trace for weight. About half an hour after casting this out, my drop-off indicator moved and I connected with what was obviously a much bigger fish. After a couple of powerful runs, the fish came up to the surface and I saw it is awesome length! re pike. The fish went 14lb 9oz, and was my second-largest pike of the season so far (beaten only by my spinner-caught 15 pounder).</string>

    <string name="winter">The infamous pike (esox lucius) is probably the most sought after predator fish in coarse angling. It is everything that we expect the top of the food chain predator should be, both in its lifestyle, nature and appearance. With it’s a flat broad, almost duck-like snout, razor like teeth, elongated streamlined body, powerful dorsal and anal fins it might simply be compared to a torpedo with jaws. Combine all of this with it natural camouflage and colours, which can vary from habitat to habitat. It is without doubt one of nature’s most apt killing machines. Throughout the years our pike have been the subject of innumerable fishy storeys, with many telling of the one that got away, the monster that lives below, and the tormentor who took your prize roach (bummer!). Many of our anglers carry these stories through generations, and every time they are‘re-spun’ the monster becomes ten pound heavier, two foot longer, or as ferocious as a swimming Rottweiler! Due to such stories establishing the true weight of the largest pike on record in the UK has been almost as tricky as catching the actual fish it might have been. According to reports, the record goes to one caught on rod and line in Llandegfedd reservoir, Wales in 1992. It is reported that the Welsh fish weighed an incredible 46lb 13ozs .Even more prestigious would be the 1945 claim for the Scottish record when it was claimed that a fish caught in Loch Lomond weighed a fantastic 47lb 11ozs. There have also been numerous unconfirmed reports of even bigger fish emanating from Northern Ireland over the years. However for various reasons I shan’t get into attempting to prove or disprove such claims. From my personal point of view, I believe the most important record of all is that of your own. Your ‘PB’ i.e. personal best which should says it all. And that’s the record you should aim to better, not a legendary figure or weight which most anglers may never see in a lifetime of stalking. Also remember your piking should be something you relax with and enjoy. Too many destroy the enjoyment by chasing impossible targets and trophy weight that others claim to have had. In the past thirty some years I have personally enjoyed every minute fishing for the freshwater shark (old esox). And yes this has included the disappointing blanks, the good days and the so called red letter days when the action comes fast and furious, double takes, more than a few high thirties and the odd ball breaker that only mate believe, because they helped you get the net under it. But remember such red letter days only come once in a blue moon and for me have been dotted over a thirty year career of hard work, intense targeting, and significant trial and errors. That said, I can confidently state that on each and every trip and session I always came away learning one thing or another. Maybe something new about the particular water I had fished that day, or the effectiveness or even ineffectiveness of particular tactics I used on that day, or simply how the weather conditions had affected the fishing on that particular venue. As for fish welfare this must become our first priority, be it from the tackle you use, to playing/landing unhooking and releasing the fish safely back to the swim alive and well and hopefully in the same condition you caught it. Giving it the best chance of survival so we can allow it to fight another day! Now getting into what basic tackle you will require i.e. rods, reels, and terminal tackle. The first thing you should be looking to invest in is quality unhooking equipment this is unfortunately the most overlooked and yet most important pieces of kit you will require for. These vital pieces of equipment should be acquired before you ever set yourselves down at the lake or river to start your pike fishing career. So let’s start as you mean to go on with fish welfare, and remember when starting out always go along with an experienced angler or guide, who hopefully will assist you in building your confidence up with handling/unhooking and releasing old esox before heading of alone. The pike may look a lean green fighting machine and as tough as nails, yes it is in its own territory under the depths in the water, but out of the water it’s the total opposite and needs respected and handled with the utmost care. I do believe that bad handling and unhooking of pike cause more damage to our sport than any other factor old esox has to put up with in its journey through life, but with the right frame of mind with the right unhooking equipment with the fishes welfare put first and foremost the future will be a lot brighter for old esox and the future pike anglers. Without question it’s all down to experience and confidence which I believe in turn is all down to hands on experience, after which the rest should start to fall into place. You should look forward to these first hurdles in pike fishing, they are by far the most important tasks you will need to complete also take pride in it as you carry on fishing for many happy years ahead. These are the basic skills which we should all learn, thus we don’t end up relying on others to handle and unhook your catch. Get in there and build your self confidence and experience, take advantage of the guide and/or experienced angler watching over you keeping on the straight and narrow. Believe me when you have achieved this and have gained those slick unhooking drills the world is your oyster. It is only through such guided hands on experience, that you will eventually gain independence and confidence, permitting you to relax and perhaps get out there and start living the dream. Who knows maybe someday you could be the one that everyone wants to be the infamous record breaker.</string>
</resources>
